<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bitcoin on dcrystalj</title><link>https://www.tomazic.pro/categories/bitcoin/</link><description>Recent content in bitcoin on dcrystalj</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 12:08:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.tomazic.pro/categories/bitcoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automating Data Backup: Protecting Your Critical Information and Peace of Mind</title><link>https://www.tomazic.pro/blog/backup-server-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 12:08:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tomazic.pro/blog/backup-server-data/</guid><description>Data loss is a real threat Having home server is great but if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it backed up you are risking losing all your data. You can lose data due to numerous things like hardware failure, ransomware, fire, theft, etc. If you google up data backup people usually recommend having some kind of raid setup but this is not solving most of the disasters that can happen.
Physical distance One of most reliable solutions is to have another server/storage in different physical location.</description></item><item><title>One Mnemonic to Rule Them All: Unlocking the Power of BIP85</title><link>https://www.tomazic.pro/blog/one-mnemonic-bip85/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 12:08:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.tomazic.pro/blog/one-mnemonic-bip85/</guid><description>Do you have multiple mnemonics written down on paper and you are afraid to mix or lose them in some catastrophic event? There exists a solution for that. BIP85 is a standard that allows you to deterministically derive new mnemonics or entropies from a single mnemonic phrase.
In this blog post, we will delve into the practicality and usefulness of BIP85, exploring how it simplifies key management and enhances security for crypto enthusiasts.</description></item></channel></rss>